Cesar Chaparro

Fresh Data Analyst

(C) WhatsApp Number +972527520220

in

Git profile

M email me

After working 7 years as a Property and Operations Manager, I decided to follow my passion for data and redirect my career. I recently graduated from the Data Analyst program at TripleTen, and I am now looking for an opportunity to join a company where I can grow and make a meaningful contribution as an Analyst.

Technical Skills:

Spreadsheets, SQL, Python, Tableau, BA, A/B testing, ML, Visualizations, Financial Analytics, Pandas, Jupyter Notebook, Anaconda, Streamlit, Statistics, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Dashboards, Storytelling, KPIs, Sklearn, VSCode, Git

Education:

2023-2024: Data Analysis Graduate at TripleTen Israel

- A 12 month intensive program in one of the best coding bootcamps for 4 years, where DA build professional skills using industry-standard tools. Course includes 12 real-data based projects.
- Final Project: A full finnancial analysis for a hardware international company to conduct a big audit
 of their sales and help them automate their existing data. I worked with SQL queries, Tableau,
 Jupyter, pandas, matplotlib, numpy, seaborn, plotly.

2023: Post-editor and encoder at Amazon

- Developmen Strings Post-Editing for Spanish (es_MX, es_US), Character Encoding, Strings
 Terminology, Machine Translation Post-Editing
- Mastering ASIN Loc Light MTPE is vital for professionals in e-commerce, particularly in product management and localization. It combines technical skills with an understanding of language nuances, enabling companies to compete in an increasingly global marketplace.

2001-2005: Business Consultancy graduate at AOSH EU, Copenhagen, Denmark

 A 4 year program to learn all skills about an organization, its various departments and internal operation schema. To manage operations, finnances and queality assessments inside the company.

1988-1993: Higher School of Languages in Valencia, Spain

• C2 degree in English.

1989-1993: High School graduate in Valencia.

Professional Experience:

2019-Present: Machine translation post-editor and character encoding editor at Amazon (Corporate).

- Edit, score and encode content for vendors and products to be on the online store for all the Spanish population in the world.
- Post-edit all content for Amazon platforms, including Prime Video, Amazon Fresh, Amazon Clinic, Amazon Stores, Machine Translation for Alessa devices in Spanish.
- Received 0 errors scores in the last 2 years on my projects and tasks by the Quality Check team.

2021-2023: Property Manager at Holiguest (Tel Aviv).

- Managed a team of 10 juniors that I created to keep a portfolio of over 100 luxury properties.
- Monitored daily tasks for check in and check out, and mainteinance so customers and owners are satisfied.
- Create and update data base for properties so they can be listed and online for renting.

2009-2024: Sales Rep. for VitalBulk Inc. Retail Food Supplements for Spain and Israel.

• Managed sales of brand food supplements in Spain and Israel regions as retailer and online sales.

2001-2007: Business Consultant at Tecnologias Aplicadas, Alicante

- Made tailor made programs for sales strategy, recruiting personnel, finnances, operations and expansion in the field of shoe manufactuting, education, software applications, lockersmith companies, construction company, indoor design, etc.
- In 2005 I was awarded as the Top Consultant on my category in United States.
- Overal I gave consulting to more than 100 small and big corportations.

Aditional Information:

- Languages: English- Advance written and spoken, Spanish- native written and spoken, Hebrew (learning), Italian- medium spoken, basic written.
- Driving license.
- Spanish and Israeli citizen, can work in Israel without restriction and in all EU continent.

I like to help:

- In 2023 volunteered in various private programs to aid families and soldiers in Israel victims of war
- In 2024 volunteered as Senior Student in TripleTen bootcamp to assist students on their progress and projects as DA.